David Hoeppner

Software Developer

University of Alberta Computing Science degree with SIP designation with 4+ years experience in Silicon Valley

mail@davidhoeppner.ca

Vancouver, Canada

github.com/dhoeppne

(669) 254-8727

in linkedin.com/in/dhoeppner

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Managed an end-to-end user experience for updating and maintaining the health, versions, and deployments of plugins for QuickBooks Online, TurboTax Online, and other Intuit products

Planned and led sprints as Scrum Lead, while working with management and project leads to exemplify Agile Development practices.

Managed a "Lunch and Learn" program at Intuit, where I would get speakers to give a 1 hour talk about various topics, including best-practices, presentation tips, and general computing knowledge.

Deployed and released containerized node services in ArgoCD via a Jenkins CI/CD pipeline to ensure >99% uptime across all managed services.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intuit

IIICUIC

Mountain View, California

05/2019 - Present Achievements/Tasks

- Created and maintained React/Node platforms to generate, deploy, and maintain Application Configurations for Quickbooks Online, TurboTax Online, and hundreds of other internal Intuit applications
- Contributed to the Server-side Rendering platform developed by my team, allowing thousands of developers to seamlessly generate static content served via AWS Lambda
- Developed software using responsible Agile practices using Jest testing on a Jenkins CI/CD pipeline

Software Developer Intuit Canada

01/2018 - 12/2018

Edmonton, Canada

Achievements/Tasks

- Built and contributed to a platform for the storage and display of millions of RUM records
- Managed a dashboard to allow plugin owners to see the performance of their plugin, and update, monitor, and release the plugin as needed
- Worked with Quickbooks developers outside my team to empathize pain points, allowing for focused and informed development planning

SKILLS



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science University of Alberta

09/2013 - 04/2020

Notes

- SIP designation

- Political Science Minor

PERSONAL PROJECTS

bgg-scraper and site-listener

 Python script to scrape Board Game Geek's database to create an easy data lookup for site-listener, which watches the deals pages of various gaming sites

VPS Network Ingress

 Kubernetes deployed NGINX reverse proxy to expose self-hosted software for friends and family

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Taekwondo Instructor

KH Min Taekwondo and Archon Taekwondo

06/2013 - 11/2017

Edmonton, AB

Tasks/Achievements

- Taught a class of 10+ adults twice weekly
- Taught under Master Sera Prokopiw while training as a 4th Dan black belt

Volunteer Tutor

Ada's Team

02/2018 - 04/2018

Edmonton, AB

Tasks/Achievements

- Assisted students with computing science questions
- Tutored once a week, as part of the Ada's team initiative at the University of Alberta, which represents marginalized groups in computing science